Okay, so let's talk about some conflict
management techniques now in this video.
Now remember, you cannot always resolve a
conflict.
So these are conflict management
techniques, right?
I mean, if you can resolve them,
yes, that's great.
So I mean, these technically are conflict
resolution techniques as well,
but you cannot always resolve a conflict,
right, but you can certainly manage them
so they don't have a negative impact on
your project.
Now, there's five conflict
management techniques
that you need to know
about for the PNP exam, right?
In reality, there might be some more, but
these are the five that you need to know.
So you've got withdrawal or avoid,
smooth or accommodate, force or direct,
then you've got compromise
and reconcile, and
then this one, collaborate
and problem solve.
Now, it's always considered.
Collaborate problem solve is generally
considered the best form.
It's a win-win scenario.
With Collaborate Problem Solve,
you get to the root cause of what the
problem is, you confront the issue,
and then you fix it and you move on.
Come to a consensus, for example.
And that is always regarded as a win-win
scenario.
However, there's these other ones as well.
So let me come back to Collaborate Problem
Solver, talk about
this in a bit more detail.
But let's talk about the others first.
So first one then, withdraw or avoid.
And withdraw or avoid literally means walk
away.
Ignore the issue.
Ignore the conflict.
Run away from the problem.
That is withdraw or avoid.
So you're in disagreement with someone and
you're just like, all
right, you know what?
I don't want to deal with this.
Or you just ignore them all together.
So you run away.
A type of thing.
So that's what withdraw or avoid is.
You're ignoring the conflict.
You're retreating from the conflict and
that kind of thing.
And that is a lose-lose scenario.
Because the conflict is still going to be
there.
the problem is still going to be there,
right?
Just running away from it, it's not going
to solve it.
Then you have smoothing or accommodating.
Smoothen or accommodating.
Now, whenever it comes to smoothing or
accommodating, right?
The best way I always
like to think of, right,
smooth and accommodating
is think of a politician.
Now, I'm not denigrating a politician or
anything like that.
Don't get me wrong, but think of a
politician, right?
Whenever you ask a politician a question,
they never answer that question.
You ask them a question,
they might address the question,
they'll talk around it, but
they'll never get to the point.
And that's exactly what smoothing or
accommodating is.
You've got this problem, you've got this
issue, right?
You've got this conflict.
And you're talking around that conflict,
right?
You're addressing it,
but you're just talking
around it, you never get to the problem.
You never get to the point, right?
You never get to the true issue,
what the real true issue is.
Again, you're talking around it.
You're maybe saying something just to
maintain relationships, right?
You don't want to upset the other person.
And so what you're not
doing really is you're not
addressing the elephant
in the room type of thing.
That's what smooth and accommodating is.
So think of it as a temporary fix,
a Band-Aid type of thing.
Or you tell somebody, just tell someone
what they want to hear.
right, you just tell them
what they want to hear
just so that, you know,
they'll remain quiet.
So that's what smooth and accommodating
is.
I mean, you know, you're addressing it,
but, you know, it's a temporary fix.
You never get into their root cause.
And that's also a
lose-lose scenario as well,
because, again, the issue
is always going to be there.
Then got this one forcing or directing,
right?
My way are the highway.
One person pushing their viewpoint at the
expense of someone else.
and that's a win-lose scenario.
The fourth thing, one person wins the
other person loses.
That is a win-lose scenario.
Then you have compromise or reconcile.
Now, compromise or reconcile is always
considered that each
party gives something up.
They give something up.
So I've got two ideas.
You've got two ideas.
You get rid of one of yours, I'll get rid
of one of mine, we'll meet halfway.
That was a compromise.
Whereas with a collaborate
we will pool all four ideas
together and come up with a
solution that we all agree to.
That's a basic difference when a
compromise and a collaborate.
In a compromise, each party gives
something up.
Whereas in a collaborate, all ideas are
pulled together, all ideas are considered,
and you come up with a solution that you
all agree to.
Now, the other basic difference between a
compromise and a reconcile is that in a
compromise each party is focused on what
they lost right they're focused on what
they lost i mean you know they're also
focused on what they've gained but they
really are you know focused on what
they've lost as well that's what they
really consider and each party generally
walks away and happy whereas in a
collaborate each party you come to a
consensus each party walks away happy
right they walk away
content so A compromise
is more of a lose-lose scenario, right?
Lose to some extent because each party has
lost something.
Whereas in a Collaborate, it's a win-win,
right?
Both parties felt like they've gained
something.
They've basically they've won.
Now even in Collaborate, there might be a
little bit of give and take as well.
In a Collaborate, there's give and take as
well.
But the big difference is in
a collaborate, you're focused
on what you've gained,
rather than what you've lost.
In a compromise, you'll be thinking,
you'll be worried about what you've lost.
So you're focused on what you've lost.
Now, generally, a collaborate,
since it's a win-win, is generally
considered the best conflict management
technique, right?
And in fact, that resolves a conflict,
that is a conflict resolution.
However, any of these could be appropriate
in the right situation.
Any of them could be appropriate,
right?
So even, if I go back, even withdraw and
avoid.
Sometimes it's, you need to walk away,
right?
Just to postpone the issue, right?
Or, you know, cooling down period,
for example.
Right, sometimes that's perfectly fine.
Or even smoother accommodating.
Sometimes you have to
tell somebody, you know, I
mean, sometimes you
have to put in a temporary fix.
We can't resolve it right now.
Right, so let's put in a temporary fix.
So let's, you know, then we'll come back
to it.
So any of these could be
appropriate in the right situation,
okay, any of these conflict
management techniques.